DUSTIN BAGGALEY

PROGRAMMER. UNIX MASTER

Download PDF

admin@keygw.com (236) - 600-2170

Profile

Unix System Administrator and Web Application Developer.

Skills

Unix Sysadmin

Talented admin and creative networker of Linux/BSD. System monitoring, scripting Guru.

Web Applications

PHP/Python/JS server side programmer. Database design.

Project Direction

Experienced manager of several large projects and CIO of my own startup.

Technical

XHTML/DOM	Jquery	OS X
CSS	PHP	Windows Server
Javascript	CVS / Git	Linux

Experience

Support Analyst

Personal Cloud Helpline

2015-Present

Provided network support for a wireless ISP in Alberta, supported Students at an online University while at the same time acted as a "Personal Digital Assistant" for the Department of Homeland Security in Iowa where I resolved technical issues for government employees.

Freelancer / Entrepreneur

Snowball Media / Key Gateway

2009-2015

Had the pleasure of raising traffic productivity for a direct marketing group, built an OOP-PHP browser-based Microsoft Office Clone, installed VOIP systems, and cultivated a cash program and stats system for my webmaster network.

Education / Career Developmen

2006-2009

Developer / Administrator

Tired of always being behind the scenes, learned the webmaster game, and worked out of pocket, learning the lessons of profitability and the cruel Keynesian laws of supply and demand. (This means, I worked days, and then again by night, cashing my paycheques into google adwords for three years until I built up a fair-sized network, and gained a good reputation in the webmaster business.) It was rewarding, though my girlfriend may have suffered some neglect throughout all the entrepreneurialism.

System Adminstrator

Net-Linx / Nexopia

2005-2006

Operated as a SAN and Oracle database cluster administrator for a newspaper chain, an IBM Blade server farm maintainer for a high-profile social networking site, facilitated high-availability server and desktop support while overhauling in-house product knowledge base and customer relationship management system. Helped a previous client with an office VOIP system and a NOC relocation.

Developer / Adminstrator Innerzone LLC

2001-2005

Programmer and Server lead for both locally hosted and managed server farms. Telecommuted from my home-office to Las Vegas daily utilizing SSH/ICQ and after hours via Palm Treo; provided cheerful support and 24/7 availability for the entire term of my employment. During this time I developed innovative web applications and payment processing systems, as well as an on demand pay-per-use video server and database failsafe mechanisms, not to mention all ancillary server and development work for the Webmaster.

Coder / Network Security

1998-2001

Zenon Corporation

Server administrator and database developer. Evolved into PHP development and world-class networking, installing a BGP multihoming router to provide hot-failover for our high-speed lines between Telus Advanced Communications and Sprint Canada bringing me into to the coveted CCNA echelon of network architects. Spearheaded projects too numerous to count, including an ISP, a webhosting provider, a webmaster program with Linux based cheque printing and much more. Also got flown out to Defcon a couple times (how fun is that!?)

Education

University of Alberta - Edmonton, AB Major in Philosophy

Dustin Baggaley - admin@keygw.com - (236) - 600-2170

1/8/2018, 1:18 PM 2 of 2